Tēlemachos Alaveras Papers and Nea Poreia Archives, 1989-2010: Finding Aid C1408
Manuscripts Division
- Series 1: Tēlemachos Alaveras Papers, 1889-2010; 47 boxes; 2 items
  - Subseries 1D: Conferences and Meetings; European Programs, 1953-2003; 3 boxes
    - Conferences-Meetings, 1953-2010; 2 boxes
      - International Conferences on Palamas, Athens, 1953-2003; 2 folders (Box 23, Folder 6-7)
        Includes autograph and typescript drafts by Alaveras; printed programs of two International Conferences on the life and work of Kōstēs Palamas that took place in Athens (November 23-26, 1993 and October 22-25, 2003); an offprint of Despoina Douka's article "To A' Diethnes Synedrio gia tē zōe kai to ergo tou Kōstē Palama" published in Nea Hestia, 1601-1602 (1994); an issue of the magazine Vivliothēkē 278 (October 2003); a poster of the symposium that held in November 1993; and published articles in Greek literary magazines.
      - Pan-Hellenic Congress of Writers, Athens (Greece), 1975 November 3-7; 2 folders (Box 23, Folder 8-9)
        Includes autograph and typescript drafts; printed copies of Alaveras's presentation; the invitation and the printed program of the conference; and clippings of Greek newspapers.
      - International Meeting of Literary, Athens (Greece), 1978 April 16-22; 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 10)
        Includes autograph manuscript drafts of Alaveras's presentation: "Dyschereies stē diadosē tēs logotechnias tōn mikrōn chōrōn"; the program of the Meeting; and one photograph of Alaveras.
      - Balkan Conference, Thessalonikē (Greece), 1978 October; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 1)
        Includes a draft of the program of the conference, which was organized by the Hetairia Logotechnōn Thessalonikēs.
      - Literary Evening: "Apotimēsē tēs prosphoras tēs genias tou '30", 1980 February; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 2)
        Includes an autograph manuscript draft of Alaveras's presentation "Genia tou trianta, procheirē diagraphē" that took place at "Ekphrasē '80" in Athens and the printed program of the event.
      - First Modern Greek Poetry Symposia, Patrai (Greece), 1981, 1989; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 3)
        Includes autograph and typescript drafts of Alaveras's presentation at the First Poetry conference (July 3-5, 1981): "Sto sēmerino kosmo"; miscellaneous notes; invitations and printed programs; photocopies of the abstracts of the talks; and a printed program of the Ninth Poetry Symposium (July 7-9, 1989).
      - Pan-Hellenic Literary Conference: "The Writing Rights," Thessalonikē (Greece), 1981 December 3-5; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 4)
        Includes autograph and typescript drafts of Alaveras's talk; a notebook; miscellaneous autograph notes; a list of the participants; a report of the conference; the poster; and newspaper clippings.
      - Spiritual Encounter of Nicosia, Nicosia (Cyprus), 1982 January 16-18; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 5)
        Includes a thank you letter by the National Association of Greek Writers of Cyprus; invitations; the printed program of the Meeting; and newspaper clippings.
      - Literary Encounter, Belgrade (Serbia), 1984 October 15-20; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 6)
        Includes an invitation and travel guides of Serbia. Handwritten note on the discarded envelope stated that there was also an event that took place in Kruševac (Kruševac, Serbia) with readings of translated texts.
      - The Twenty-third Spring Symposium of Byzantine Studies. "Salonica: The Second City," University of Birmingham, 1989 March 18-21; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 7)
        Includes the registration form and other pertinent to the Symposium material.
      - Epistēmoniko Symposio "Leontios Machairas-Geōrgios Voustrōnios, dyo Chronika tēs Mesaiōnikēs Kyprou," Nicosia (Cyprus), 1996 September 21; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 10)
        Includes the printed program of the symposium.
      - 2nd Balkan Meeting of Translation in Sofia (Bulgaria), 1989; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - 26th Dēmētria. First Literary Meet on Postwar Prose, 1991 October 31- November 2; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous, 1949-2010; 2 folders (Box 24, Folder 11-12)
        Includes printed programs and invitations of several literary lectures, symposia, or exhibitions.
    - European Programs, 1985-1992; 2 boxes
      - Funding for Translations of Contemporary Greek Literature, 1989; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 13)
        Includes handwritten notes by Alaveras and printed material.
      - Funding for Translations of Contemporary Greek Literature, 1989; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Copyright Law in the European Community, 1992; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 1E: Literary Competitions and Awards, 1977-2007; 2 boxes; 2 items
    This subseries consists of autograph manuscripts and typescripts, as well as printed material regarding literary competitions and awards that Alaveras received for his published works.
    This subseries has been organized in a chronogical order.
    - Literary Competitions, 1963-1991; 2 folders (Box 25, Folder 3-4)
      Includes Alaveras's notes; printed material regarding the literary competitions Dēmētria and Vellidē; abstracts and comments of the theatrical plays that were submitted for the competitions; the competition postings; a book of Minutes of the jury for a literary contest for the newspaper Thessalonikē dated 1966; and the Minutes of the International Film Festival of Thessalonikē dated 1989.
    - Ap'aphormē, 1977-1978; 2 folders (Box 25, Folder 5-6)
      Includes the National Literary Award for Alaveras's book Ap'aphormē and congratulation letters. Correspondents included are: Papaditsas, D. P.; Papadakē, Eleutheria I.; Vaphopoulos, G. Th.; Varverēs, Giannēs; Stamelos, Dēmētrēs; Papathemelēs, Stelios; Papadēmas, Adamantios; Kalphopoulos, Chrēstos; Paraskeuopoulou, Kitsa; Tatsēs, Michalēs; Spetzopoulos, Petros; Zitsaia, Chrysanthē; Stergiopoulos, Kōstas; Sarantē, Galateia; Dalmatē, Margarita; Iōannidēs, I.D.; Sphakianakēs, Giannēs; Kokkinos, Dēmosthenēs; Kontou, Nana; Thoividopoulos, Dēmētrēs; Papadakē, Eleutheria; and Agathopoulou, Maria. There are also clippings of Greek newspapers and one issue of the magazine Physiolatrikos kosmos (January-March 1978) regarding the award.
    - National Chronicle-Witness Award (see also Box 42, folder 10 for clippings), 1991; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 7)
      Includes autograph notes by Alaveras; a telegram; and the printed program of the National Literary Awards. Alaveras received the Chronicle-Witness Award for his work S'eutheia grammē.
    - National Awards for Writing Theatre Projects, 1993; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 8)
      Includes Alaveras's autograph manuscript drafts of his reviews on the submitted theatrical plays to the competition and incoming correspondence from the Hellenic Ministry of Culture.
    - Logotechnika Vraveia 1998 (see Box 43, folder 5), 1998-1999; 1 item
    - Logotechniko Vraveio Phreiderikou Mathious, 2002; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Kratika Vraveia Logotechnias [National Literary Awards], 2004-2008; 2 folders (Box 25, Folder 10-11)
      Includes a list of the awards that had been given from 1956 to 2003; the minutes of the meetings of the committee (2004-2005); Alaveras's autograph lists of the names of the recipients of the awards for 2004 and 2005; clippings of Greek newspapers and literary magazines regarding the grant prize of literature that Alaveras received in 2007 for all of his work; a poster; and congratulation letters.
    - Kratika Logotechnika Vraveia 2006-2007 [State Literary Awards 2006-2007], 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 12)
      Includes congratulation letters from friends and colleagues of Alaveras. Printed material has been transfered to Box 43 (folder 6).
    - Awards, 1987-2007; 1 box (Box 26)
      Includes five awards that Alaveras's received either for his books or for Nea Poreia.
  - Subseries 1F: Documents, 1957-1974; 2 boxes
    This subseries consists of Tēlemachos Alaveras's personal documents.
    - School Report Cards and Certificate, 1932-1934; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Cerificate of Municipal Registry; Passports; Driving Licence; Identification Cards; Electoral Booklet; Student Booklet, 1946-2006; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Military, 1949-1976; 2 folders (Box 27, Folder 3-4)
      Includes miscellaneous military documents; Alaveras's autograph and typescript drafts of a paper entitled "Historia phorētōn hoplōn stratou [History of Mobile Infantry Weapons] dated March 20, 1952; a Christmas speech dated December 25, 1951; drafts regarding the military school; a poem; and a book review.
    - Financial, 1962-1977; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 5)
      Includes two budget expenses books and a few loose sheets.
    - Invoice Books, 1959-1968; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Accounting Books, 1957-1968; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Certificates; Insurances, 1962-1976; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Lease Agreements & Correspondence, 1964-1969; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Documentation; Private Agreements, 1959-1969; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 8)
      Includes documentation for evidence to practice professional activity; private agreements; and tax-assessment of Internal Revenue Service (IRS).
    - Private Agreement with the film producer and photographer Geōrgios Christophoridēs, 1969; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Private Agreement with the Mount Athos Heritage Preservation Center (KeDAK in Greek), 1984-1985; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Trip to Poland, 1983; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 11)
      Includes correspondence with the Greek Ministry of Culture and the Greek Ministry of Foreign Affairs; a passport; tourist maps; and business cards.
    - Miscellaneous, 1954-2002; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 12)
      Includes miscellaneous certificates, applications, an autograph manuscript by Alaveras regarding his great-grandfather, Geōrgios Chrēstou Alaveras. There is also a tiny wooden icon of Saint Barbara from Alaveras's childhood.
  - Subseries 1G: Writings by Others, 1920-2010; 11 boxes
    This subseries consists of autograph manuscripts and typescripts, as well as page proofs of works by several Greek authors. Tēlemachos Alaveras had the philological editing of most of these works.
    This subseries has been arranged in an alphabetical order by the last name of the author or the organization that was responsible for the publication. In the case of more than one work by the same author then the arrangement has been made by chronological order.
    - Astiko Hellēniko Spiti Thessalonikēs, 1880-1912 [The Bourgeois Greek House of Thessaloniki, 1880 - 1912]. The Folklore and Ethnological Museum of Macedonia, Thessalonikē., 1985; 3 folders (Box 28, Folder 1-3)
      Includes autograph and typescript drafts, as well as page proofs of the guide book to the exhibition on the urban Greek house in Thessalonikē. Tēlemachos Alaveras had the philological editing of the book.
    - Bakirtzēs, Charalampos. "Hē ochyrōsē tēs Thessalonikēs," Vyzantina 7 (289-341, 461-495), 1975; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Christianopoulos, Dinos. "Phrontistērio", 1947 September; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 5)
      Includes an autograph manuscript draft of a short novel entitled: "Phrontistērio."
    - Dēmou, Dēmētrēs St. Oneirologio. Hetairia Logotechnōn Thessalonikēs, 1962-2000; 2 folders (Box 28, Folder 6-7)
      Includes page proofs.
    - Dēmou, Dēmētrēs St. Skorpia phylla hēmerologiou, 1973; 2 folders (Box 28, Folder 8-9)
      Includes page proofs of Dēmou's book Skorpia phylla hēmerologiou as it was typesetted for the Hetaireia Logotechnōn Thessalonikēs.
    - Dēmou, Dēmētrēs St. Skorpia phylla hēmerologiou, 1973; 2 folders (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
    - Dēmou, Dēmētrēs St.. Translations, 1984-1990; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 3)
      Includes Dēmou's translations from German into Greek of the following works: Pros tis tropikes chōres by Kaizerlingk, Herman; To terastio typhlopontiko [ The Burrow] by Franz Kafka; notes of the book Topoi of Marie Luise Kaschnitz; Hē mache, hē machē by Alfred Doblin; Ho skouphos by Thomas Bernhard; and Anthypolochagos Gkoustl by Arthur Schnitzler.
    - Dēmou, Dēmētrēs St., 1984-1990; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 4)
      Includes autograph notes on loose sheets that were kept by Dēmou when he was sick and not able to talk. These notes were sent to Alaveras, according to a handwritten note by Roula Alavera on the discarded envelope.
    - Douka-Kampitoglou, Aikaterinē. Hē parousia tou Saixpēr ston hellēniko chōro, 1981; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Geōrgiadēs, Thanasēs. "Poiēsē stē Thessalonikē", undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 6)
      Includes page proofs and typescripts with handwritten corrections and additions.
    - Hypourgeion Voreiou Hellados. Thrakē-Mikros hodēgos, 1980; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 7)
      Includes page proofs in English, French, and Greek.
    - Hypourgeion Voreiou Hellados. Thrakē-mikros hodēgos, 1980; 2 folders (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
      Includes autograph manuscripts and typescripts in Greek; black-and-white photographs of monuments of Thrace; and printed editions of the short guide to Thrace.
    - Iōannou, Michaēl Chatzēs. Astygraphia Thessalonikēs: ētoi topographikē perigraphē tēs Thessalonikēs, 1976; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 3)
      Includes galley proofs.
    - Korphēs, Petros. Reviews, undated; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 4)
      Includes autograph manuscript drafts of reviews of the work by Michalēs Peranthēs and Paraskeuas Mēliopoulos.
    - Lampele, Phoula, 1978; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 5)
      Includes page proofs of an untitled work by Lampele, as well as typescripts of short novels entitled: "Phata Mornkana"; "Lais"; "Gavriella"; and "Martha."
    - Laographiko kai Ethnologiko Mouseio Makedonias-Thrakēs. Prōtē gnōrimia me ton paradosiako politismo tēs periochēs Phlōrinas. Hodēgos ekthesēs, 1993-2004; 4 folders (Box 30, Folder 6-9)
      Includes galley proofs (Greek and English) and page proofs; a model of the book; autograph notes by Alaveras; typescripts; and a printed guide book of Phlōrina. The book was published in Thessalonikē.
    - Laographiko kai Ethnologiko Mouseio Makedonias-Thrakēs. Prōtē gnōrimia me ton paradosiako politismo tēs periochēs Phlōrinas. Hodēgos ekthesēs, 1993-2004; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 1)
      Includes page proofs in English.
    - Makrēs, Solōn. Katalogos tōn ergōn. Athens, 1994; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Mantadakē, Smaragda. Art Kor, henas synchronos herōas. Meletē sto diēgēma tou Tēlemachou Alavera me titlo: Art Kor., 2009; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 3)
      Includes a copy of Mantadakēs's study on Alaveras's novel Arta Kor; her biography; and list of her published works.
    - Markopoulos, Giōrgos. Hevdomē symphōnia, 1968; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 4)
      Includes copies of a collection of printed poems entitled "Hevdomē symphōnia" written by Markopoulos, which according to Alaveras's note this was an illegal and rare edition during the junta. There are also some other poems on loose sheets of paper.
    - Meraklēs, Michalēs. [ Logotechnia]; "Ho dēmosiographos kai kritikos, Petros Hōrologas," AMss, undated; 1 folder (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Moskōph, Kōstēs. Hē ethnikē kai koinōnikē syneidēsē stēn Hellada, 1830-1909: ideologia tou metapratikou chōrou: historikē meletē, 1972; 3 folders (Box 31, Folder 6-8)
      Includes autograph manuscript drafts by Moskōph. A handwritten note by Alaveras on the discarded envelope stated that one copy of the page proofs (folder, no.3) was the "seventh proofreading - G.P. Savvidēs." It was published in Thessalonikē; no publishing house is mentioned.
    - Moskōph, Kōstēs. Hē ethnikē kai koinōnikē syneidēsē stēn Hellada, 1830-1909: ideologia tou metapratikou chōrou: historikē meletē, 1972; 4 folders (Box 32, Folder 1-4)
      See above.
    - Nikēphorou, Tolēs. To magiko chali: trianta erōtika poiēmata [n.p.], 1980; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 5)
      Includes page proofs and typescripts. It was published in Thessalonikē.
    - Nikēphorou, Tolēs. Me tē phōtia sta matia. Ta poiēmata 1978-1982, 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 6)
      Includes page proofs. It was published in Thessalonikē.
    - Nikolaou, Argyrēs. Phengarotropion, undated; 1 folder (Box 32, Folder 7)
      Includes page proofs and typescripts with handwritten corrections.
    - Papasiōpēs, Paulos, 1920-1969; 3 folders (Box 33, Folder 1-3)
      Includes typescripts with autograph annotations of several articles by Papasiōpēs that were published either in Nea Poreia or other Greek literary magazines and newspapers of Athens and Thessalonikē both in Greek and French; autograph manuscripts and typescripts of articles translated from French into Greek; a short biographical statement; lists of his articles and translations; clippings of Greek newspapers; black-and-white photographs; incoming correspondence from Kōstas Ouranēs, Lilika Nakou, Geōrgios Kotzioulas, Giannēs Kōnstantinou Kordatos, and Henri Barbusse. There is also a notebook entitled "Souvenirs" dated 1930-1934.
    - Pentzikēs, Nikos Gavriēl, undated; 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 4)
      Includes autograph manuscript drafts of the first and second paragraphs of the novel Apokatastasē.
    - Pylorōph-Sōtēroudē, Sonia. Poiēmata tou '83, 1984; 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Sachinēs, Apostolos. Mesopolemikoi kai metapolemikoi pezographoi, 1979; 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 6)
      Includes autograph manuscripts.
    - Samara, Zōe. "Hē poiētikē tēs mythoplasias sto ergo tou Tēlemachou Alavera" in Kaniskion philias: timētikos tomos gia ton Guy Michel Saunier, epimeleia Karagiannis-Moser, Emmanuelle, Eleutheria Giakoumakē. Athēna, 2002; 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Saras, Thōmas. Mēnymata elpidas. Poiēmata, 1971-1972; 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 8)
      Includes autograph manuscript drafts and a letter from Saras to Tēlemachos Alaveras.
    - Scholes, Robert; Klaus, Carl H. Stoicheia tou Dramatos, tr. Parisē, Aristea. Thessalonikē: Ekdoseis Kōnstantinidē, 1984-1985; 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 9)
      Includes autograph manuscripts of Parisē's translation and printed proofs by Alaveras.
    - Scholes, Robert; Klaus, Carl H. Stoicheia tou Dramatos, tr. Parisē, Aristea. Thessalonikē: Ekdoseis Kōnstantinidē, 1985; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Stogiannidēs, G.X. Miscellaneous Poems. AMss, undated; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Tararas, Nikos. Poiēmata, 1981; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Themelēs, Geōrgios. "To idiaitero tetradio mou"; "Hypervatiko paramythi"; "Hē pneumatikē Thessalonikē", 1955; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 4)
      Includes loose autograph manuscript drafts and a notebook.
    - Themelēs, Geōrgios. To pouli kai to thērio, undated; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 5)
      Includes page proofs of the theatric play in three acts.
    - Thoividopoulos, Dēmētrēs. Poetry, 1982; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 6)
      Includes autograph and typescript drafts of miscellaneous poems.
    - Tsaloumas, Dimitris, Anastasē 1967 kai triptycho gia mia deutera parousia, 1982; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 7)
      Includes a bound autograph manuscript by Tsaloumas.
    - Vamvakas, Petros. Peri tēn apeleutherōsin tēs Dytikēs Thrakēs. Athēnai, 1986; 1 folder (Box 34, Folder 8)
      Includes autograph and typescript drafts, as well as a biographical statement.
    - Vasileiadēs, Stylianos. Koitasma K.P. Kavaphē, 2000-2001; 2 folders (Box 34, Folder 9-10)
    - Vasileiadēs, Stylianos. Koitasma K.P. Kavaphē, 2000-2001; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Vistōnitēs, Anastasēs, 1973-1985; 2 folders (Box 35, Folder 2-3)
      Includes a notebook entitled '"Hēmerologio" 1973 18 Noemvriou"' containing drafts of short essays written by Vistōnitēs and dated 1977; typescripts with handwritten annotations of two more essays: "To timēma" (1984) and "Logotechnia kai epistēmē" (1985); there are also autograph manuscripts of several short stories dated 1978.
    - Votaniatēs, Agis. Erōtes pisō ap' tis maskes. Poiēmata. Thessalonikē, 1986; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 4)
      Includes typescripts.
    - Votaniatēs, Agis. "Hē psicha tēs psychēs"; "Hesperida"; "Hē vasileia" AMss, 1988; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Votaniatēs, Agis. "Epistoles stēn kyria", undated; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 6)
      Includes copies of autograph manuscripts, which according to a handwritten note is entitled "Epistoles stēn kyria."
    - Zakythinos, Alexis D. Ta aparaitēta gegonota, 1975; 1 folder (Box 35, Folder 7)
      Includes page proofs and a letter from Zakythinos to Alaveras.
    - Zēras, Alexēs; Tolēs Kazantzēs; Alexandros Argyriou; et al. Hē kritikē gia ta vivlia tou Tēlemachou Alavera. Hetairia Logotechnōn Thessalonikēs, 2007; 2 folders (Box 35, Folder 8-9)
    - Zēras, Alexēs; Tolēs Kazantzēs; Alexandros Argyriou; et al. Hē kritikē gia ta vivlia tou Tēlemachou Alavera. Hetairia Logotechnōn Thessalonikēs, 2007; 2 folders (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1930-1999; 4 folders (Box 36, Folder 3-6)
      Consists of autograph manuscripts and typescripts of short stories, poems, essays, translations, and book reviews. Included are writings by Thales Rētoridēs: "Triantaphyllenia zōē"; Mēnas Dēmakes; Giōrgos Delios: "Skies"; several poems by Zōe Karellē; Arēs Diktaios; Dēmētrēs A. Dēmētriadēs; Tasos Korphēs; Vasileios Laourdas; Jean Paul Mestas; Bampēs Nintas; Anthou Pōgōnitē; Giannēs Varverēs; Manos Eleutheriou; O. Sans; Tasia Adam; Nikos Papanas; Stauros Vavourēs; Takēs Varvitsiōtēs (the poem "Exoristos"); Andreas Angelakēs; a manuscript by an unknown author entitled "Delphikes giortes" with a handwritten copy of Angelos Sikelianos's letter dated March 12, 1925; and a book review by Panos K. Thasitēs (he signs as Vasiles Nēsiōtēs).
      There is also an incomplete essay by Vasilēs Phrankos entitled: "Kritikē henos kritikou"; the poem "Symphōnia tou Septemvriou" by Milosz, O. V. de L. in Greek translation by Tasos Korphēs; the poem "Gynaika tēs Genova" by Dino Campana in Greek translation by Nikos Spanias; two translations by Takēs Varvitsiōtēs: "Ōdē sto Phenteriko Gkarthia Lorka" and "Ho cheimōnas mas"; book reviews written by G. Kyriakou; an interview of Cristino Sangiglio. Included are talks by Tadeusz Szymanski and Heinz Kunio that were given at the Jewish Community of Thessalonikē (1988).
      Included also are: poetry contest of college students; a college paper on Chalastra of Thessalonikē; two papers of high school students; typescripts of poems of Greek college students that participated in a poetry contest. A typescript of a talk by Kounio, Chaints Salvatōr, "Apo ton Antisēmitismo tou Tritou Raich stē Nychta tōn Krystallōn kai ten telikē lysē tou Hevraikou provlēmatos."
    - Talks; Articles; Reviews; Translations; Essays; Dissertation on Alaveras's Works, 1955-2010; 3 boxes
      - Alavera, Roula, 1997; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - Georgiadēs, Thanasēs, 1986; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 8)
        Includes photocopies of typescripts with criticism on Alaveras's books.
      - Kōtopoulos, Triantaphyllos. [Hē Thessalonikē sto ergo tōn Thessalonikeōn pezographōn. Univeristy of Iōannina-Department of Philology. PhD Thesis, 2001-2002; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 9)
        Includes part of a doctorate thesis on the works of Alaveras with autograph corrections or comments by him.
      - Makrēs, Solōn. "Pezographoi tēs Thessalonikēs", 1972-1973; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 1)
        Includes two letters from Makrēs, as well as an untitled and incomplete typescript copy of a review entitled " Pezographoi tēs Thessalonikēs," published in Kritika phylla, 1973-1974.
      - Mauridēs, Panagiōtēs. "Henas seismos stē logotechnia", 1994 March 18; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 2)
        Includes Maurides's autograph manuscripts of his talk given at the Hetairia Logotechnōn Thessalonikēs [Writers' Association of Thessalonikē] based on Alaveras's novel Amixia. There are also three color photographs of the event.